<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UVA Biocomplexity Institute</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>General Overview of the Project</title>
      <link>/findings/general-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/general-overview/</guid>
      <description>While this page is optional, it probably makes sense to have one weighted at the top (see the front matter at the top of this Rmd file) that gives a general overview of the project. This could be something like the final poster while the other pages highlight more in-depth observations. Here is a general schema of what should be covered throughout your website:
Main Findings [Here you will describe the results and include important visualizations from your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Section One</title>
      <link>/findings/results-section-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/results-section-one/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Examples Page If you want to add in an image on an Rmd file, use this link here. It ends up being a little tricky, but as long as you have created a folder to insert your images, you can just use some markdown code or html to insert images in the format you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Section Two</title>
      <link>/findings/results-section-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/results-section-two/</guid>
      <description>[Here you will describe the data discoversy process, the data used, and the methods employed for this single page. Since you already have a Project Overview and Data &amp;amp; Methods tabs, you probably want to keep this first paragraph fairly short and use the rest of the document to walk your readers through your analyses.]
Main Findings [Here you will describe the results and include important visualizations from your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Section Three: Cooccurrence and Bigrams</title>
      <link>/findings/results-section-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/results-section-three/</guid>
      <description>[Here you will describe the data discoversy process, the data used, and the methods employed for this single page. Since you already have a Project Overview and Data &amp;amp; Methods tabs, you probably want to keep this first paragraph fairly short and use the rest of the document to walk your readers through your analyses.]
How do Black and White soldiers talk about gender roles? In addition to analyzing race relations between soldiers, we want to see how gender roles were discussed amongst soldiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/</guid>
      <description>2020 NEH American Soldier Summer Project Data Our data is from a comprehensive surveying project by the US military during World War II. We are particularly interested in Survey 32, 144, and 190 which contain multiple choice questions ranging from demographic information, thoughts on the army, thoughts on the war, career plans, etc.
Survey 32 was administered to both black and white soldiers in order to studying attitudes of and towards black soldiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/</guid>
      <description>2020 NEH American Soldier Summer Project The objective of this project is to use a novel data source to garner new insights into race, gender, and spacial relationships between army soldiers during world war II. The project uses transcribed data from a crowdsourcing platform to create textual data. The survey that we are focusing on is Survey 32 which is a survey that includes one multiple choice question on whether or not soldiers want separated or integrated outfits and two response questions giving space for them to extend on their multiple choice answer and their sentiments on the survey as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/</guid>
      <description>UVA Data Science for the Public Good Program The Data Science for the Public Good (DSPG) Young Scholars program is a summer immersive program held at the Biocomplexity Institute’s Social and Decision Analytics division (SDAD). In its seventh year, the program engages students from across the country to work together on projects that address state, federal, and local government challenges around critical social issues relevant in the world today. DSPG young scholars conduct research at the intersection of statistics, computation, and the social sciences to determine how information generated within every community can be leveraged to improve quality of life and inform public policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiling S32 Respondents</title>
      <link>/findings/s32_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/s32_website/</guid>
      <description>Who Are the Soldiers? Survey 32 was given out to soldiers in 1943, approximately 5 years before the military was integrated. The survey was passed out to 7442 black soldiers and 4793 white soldiers and asked for basic demographic information, career aspirations, and more but of interests to us, Survey 32 asked the soldiers for their opinions on integration of military outfits. Our questions of interest are regarding age, education, enlistment, state, community type, and of course their opinions on outfits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey 144 Writeup</title>
      <link>/findings/eda_s144/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/eda_s144/</guid>
      <description>Who Are the Soldiers? Survey 144 was given out to soldiers in 1944, approximately 4 years before the military was integrated. The survey was passed out to 4678 black soldiers and focused on post-war aspirations and plans of the soldiers. Of particular interest to us however, is the soldiers&#39; responses to question if their lives would be better after the war.
## age edu enlist state community ## 1 24 SOME COLLEGE DRAFTED PACIFIC Large City ## 2 &amp;lt;=18 SOME HIGH/TRADE SCHOOL DRAFTED EAST NORTH ATLANTIC Large City ## 3 23 HIGH SCHOOL DRAFTED EAST SOUTH ATLANTIC Large City ## 4 22 SOME COLLEGE DRAFTED EAST NORTH ATLANTIC Large City ## 5 26-29 SOME HIGH/TRADE SCHOOL DRAFTED WEST SOUTH ATLANTIC City ## 6 26-29 8TH GRADE DRAFTED WEST SOUTH ATLANTIC City ## 7 &amp;lt;=18 SOME HIGH/TRADE SCHOOL DRAFTED EAST SOUTH ATLANTIC Large City ## 8 20 HIGH SCHOOL DRAFTED EAST SOUTH ATLANTIC Large City ## 9 &amp;lt;NA&amp;gt; 7TH GRADE DRAFTED EAST NORTH ATLANTIC Farm ## 10 25 7TH GRADE DRAFTED MIDDLE ATLANTIC Large City ## better ## 1 &amp;lt;NA&amp;gt; ## 2 Worse ## 3 Same ## 4 Undecided ## 5 &amp;lt;NA&amp;gt; ## 6 Undecided ## 7 Better ## 8 Same ## 9 &amp;lt;NA&amp;gt; ## 10 Better Age Age was not collected on a continuous scale and was discretized into a few different age groups.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>