<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UVA Biocomplexity Institute</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Demographic Analyses of Black Soldiers</title>
      <link>/findings/eda_s144/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/eda_s144/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Who Are the Soldiers? Survey 144 was given out to soldiers in 1944, approximately 4 years before the military was integrated. The survey was passed out to 4,678 black soldiers and focused on post-war plans and aspirations of the soldiers. We were particularly interested in how the soldiers thought their lives would be better after the war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Section Three: Cooccurrence and Bigrams</title>
      <link>/findings/results-section-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/results-section-three/</guid>
      <description>[Here you will describe the data discoversy process, the data used, and the methods employed for this single page. Since you already have a Project Overview and Data &amp;amp; Methods tabs, you probably want to keep this first paragraph fairly short and use the rest of the document to walk your readers through your analyses.]
How do Black and White soldiers talk about gender roles? In addition to analyzing race relations between soldiers, we want to see how gender roles were discussed amongst soldiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/antiquated/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/antiquated/methods/</guid>
      <description>2020 NEH American Soldier Summer Project Data Our data is from a comprehensive surveying project by the US military during World War II. We are particularly interested in Survey 32, 144, and 190 which contain multiple choice questions ranging from demographic information, thoughts on the army, thoughts on the war, career plans, etc.
Survey 32 was administered to both black and white soldiers in order to studying attitudes of and towards black soldiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/antiquated/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/antiquated/overview/</guid>
      <description>2020 NEH American Soldier Summer Project The objective of this project is to use a novel data source to garner new insights into race, gender, and spacial relationships between army soldiers during world war II. The project uses transcribed data from a crowdsourcing platform to create textual data. The survey that we are focusing on is Survey 32 which is a survey that includes one multiple choice question on whether or not soldiers want separated or integrated outfits and two response questions giving space for them to extend on their multiple choice answer and their sentiments on the survey as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/antiquated/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/antiquated/team/</guid>
      <description>UVA Data Science for the Public Good Program The Data Science for the Public Good (DSPG) Young Scholars program is a summer immersive program held at the Biocomplexity Institute’s Social and Decision Analytics division (SDAD). In its seventh year, the program engages students from across the country to work together on projects that address state, federal, and local government challenges around critical social issues relevant in the world today. DSPG young scholars conduct research at the intersection of statistics, computation, and the social sciences to determine how information generated within every community can be leveraged to improve quality of life and inform public policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Data &amp;amp; Methods [not done yet]
Our data is from a comprehensive surveying project by the US military during World War II. We are particularly interested in Survey 32, 144, and 190 which contain multiple choice questions ranging from demographic information, thoughts on the army, thoughts on the war, career plans, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Project Overview Our work is part of the broader American Soldier in World War II initiative, based out of Virginia Tech, striving to make available to scholars and to the public a remarkable collection of written reflections on war and military service by American soldiers who served during the Second World War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  UVA Data Science for the Public Good The Data Science for the Public Good (DSPG) Young Scholars program is a summer immersive program held at the Biocomplexity Institute’s Social and Decision Analytics division (SDAD). In its seventh year, the program engages students from across the country to work together on projects that address state, federal, and local government challenges around critical social issues relevant in the world today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race Relations</title>
      <link>/findings/race_overall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/race_overall/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Why we care about this topic and what we would like to learn
 Exploratory Data Analysis Who Are the Soldiers? Survey 32 was given out to soldiers in 1943, approximately 5 years before the military was integrated. The survey was passed out to 7442 black soldiers and 4793 white soldiers and asked for basic demographic information, career aspirations, and more but of interests to us, Survey 32 asked the soldiers for their opinions on integration of military outfits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey 195 Writeup</title>
      <link>/findings/gender_s195/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/gender_s195/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In addition to race relations in the Army, we are also focused on perspectives on women and gender within the military. The questions and responses are mostly geared towards WACs, which are Women&#39;s Army Corps members. In addition to survey 32, which captures textual data on gender in teh Army, a survey was given out in January of 1945 to capture perspectives of male soldiers on their WAC counterparts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Models</title>
      <link>/findings/topic_models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/topic_models/</guid>
      <description>Topic Model Networks A topic model put simply models the topics in a piece of text and the words that are associated with each topic. Naturally, words may fall in multiple topics and the model accounts for this by giving each topic a probability distribution over the words. A Topic Model Network is a useful way to visualize the topics and the words associated with each topic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>